[SOUND] We started with alpha i's being uniform, the same for
[صوت] لقد بدأنا مع وجود ألفا بشكل موحد،
all data points, one over n, and now we want to change them to focus
كمثل جميع نقاط التدريب، واحد فوق n، ونريد الآن تغييرها
more on those difficult data points where we're making mistakes.
للتركيز أكثر على تلك نقاط البيانات الصعبة، حيث نقوم بالأخطاء.
So the question is where did f t make mistakes or
ولهذا، فإن السؤال، أين ينتج أخطاء عن ft،
what data points f t got right.
أو متى تكون نقاط البيانات ft صحيحة؟
If f t got a particular data point,
إذا كان يوجد في ft نقاط بيانات محددة،
xi right, we want to decrease alpha i because we got it right.
تكون فيها xi صحيحة، فإننا نود تقليل ألفا i، لأننا حصلنا عليها صحيحة.
But if we got xi wrong, then want to increase our phi so the next
ولكن في حالة حصلنا على xi خاطئة، فإننا سنود زيادة ألفا i لدينا،
decision style we classify our homes in and does better in this particular input.
ولهذا سنقوم بتصنيف منازلنا في أسلوب القرار التالي، ويؤدي بشكل أفضل في تلك المدخلات المحددة.
Again, the AdaBoost theorem provides us with a slightly intimidating formula for
ومجددًا، فإن نظرية AdaBoost تقدم إلينا بصيغة تهويل بشكل ما،
how to update the weights out for i.
حول كيفية تحديث الأحجام بالنسبة لi.
But if you take a moment to interpret it, we'll see this one is extremely intuitive,
ولكنك إن تفحصناها للحظات، فسنرى أنها بديهية للغاية،
and there's something quite nice.
وأنه يوجد شيء ما جيد.
So let's take a quick look at it.
ولهذا، دعونا نلقِ نظرة سريعة عليها.
So it says that alpha i gets an update depending on whether on ft
ولهذا، فهي توضح حصول ألفا i على تحديث، يعتمد على إذا ما كانت ft
gets the data point right because this is correct or whether ft makes a mistake.
قد حصلت على نقاط البيانات بشكل صحيح، وبشكل صائب، أو أنها قامت به بشكل خطأ.
In this we'll see we're going to increase the weight of data points where we
وفي هذه الحالة، فإننا سنلاحظ أننا سنقوم بزيادة حجم نقاط البيانات
made mistakes and we're going to decrease the weight of data points we got right.
عندما نقوم بأخطاء ، وسنقوم بتقليل حجمها عندما نقوم بذلك على الوجه الصحيح.
So let's take a look at this.
دعونا نلقِ نظرة على هذا.
So let's take one xi and lets suppose that we got it correct.
دعونا نستعرض واحد xi ودعونا نفترض أننا حصلنا عليه بشكل صحيح.
So, we're the top line here and notice that this equation depends on
ولهذا، فهي على السطر العلوي، ولاحظ أن المعادلة تعتمد عليها،
whatever the coefficients that was assigned to this classifier.
مهما كانت المعاملات التي تم تعيينها لهذا المصنف،
So, the classifier was good.
ولهذا، كان المصنف جيدًا.
We only changed a way to more but
قمنا فقط بتغيير الطريقة للأكثر،
if the classifiers was terrible we're going to change the weights less.
ولكن إذا كانت المصنفات سيئة، فسنقوم بتغيير الأحجام للأقل.
So, let's say the classifier was good and we gave it weight 2.3.
لذا دعونا نقل إن المصنف كان جيدًا، وقمنا بإعطاء حجمه 2.3.
So what we're doing here, we're looking at the formula,
لذا، ما نقوم به هنا، هو أننا نقوم برؤية الصيغة،
we're multiplying alpha i by e to the -w hat t, which is 2.3.
نقوم بضرب ألفا i في e مرفوعًا لأس (Ŵ (t-، والذي يكون 2.3.
And if you take your calculator out, you see that this is 0.1.
وإذا استخدمت الآلة الحاسبة، فستلاحظ أن الناتج 0.1.
So, we're taking the data points to our right, and
ولهذا، قمنا بنقل نقاط البيانات إلى الجانب الصحيح الخاص بنا،
we multiply the weight of those data points, by 0.1, so dividing by 10.
وقمنا بضرب الحجم لنقاط البيانات تلك في 0.1، ولذا قمنا بالقسمة على 10.
So what effect does that do?
إذًا، ما التأثير الذي يُحدثه ذلك؟
We're going to decrease the importance of this data point
سنقوم بتقليل أهمية نقاط البيانات هذه،
ff xi, yi, so this particular data point.
ff, xi, وyi، ولذا، فهي نقاط البيانات المحددة تلك.
Now let's look at a case where we got the data point correct but
ولذا، دعونا نلقِ نظرة، على حالة تكون فيها نقاط البيانات صحيحة،
the cost that we learn is random.
لأن التكلفة التي تعلمناها عشوائية.
So, it had to wait zero just like we discussed a few slides ago.
ولهذا، فإنها ستبقى صفرًا، كما قمنا بمناقشة ذلك في الشرائح القليلة السابقة.
So it's overall weight 0.5 is weight 0.
ولهذا، فإن الحجم الكلي لها 0.5 هو الحجم 0.
In this case we're multiplying the coefficient L5, but e to the minus 0.
ونقوم في هذه الحالة، بضرب المعامل L5، في e مرفوعة لأس -0،
Which is = 1, What does that mean?
ويساوي ذلك 1، فماذا يعنيه ذلك؟
That means that when I keep the importance of this data point
يعني أنني عندما أقوم بجعل الأهمية لنقاط البيانات تلك متساوية،
the same, that also makes a ton of sense.
فإن ذلك يبدو منطقيًا،
So this was a classified that was terrible and we gave it a weight of 0,
ولهذا، تم تصنيف ذلك على أنه مروع، وأعطيناه حجمًا يساوي 0،
we are going to ignore it, and so since we are ignoring it we are not changing
وسنقوم بتجاهلها، وبما أننا سنقوم بتجاهلها، فلن تقوم بتغيير أي شيء
anything about how we rate all data points we are just going to keep going as if
حول كيفية تقييم جميع نقاط البيانات، وسنقوم فقط بالإبقاء عليها كما هي،
nothing's happened because nothing's changed on their overall assemble.
كما لو أنه لم يحدث أي شيء، حيث لم يتغير أي شيء في كامل مجموعتها.
Now let's look at the opposite case when we actually made mistakes so
ودعونا الآن نلقِ نظرة على الحالة الأخرى، عندما نقوم بأخطاء بالفعل،
let's say that we got xi incorrect so we made a mistake.
ولهذا دعونا نقل إن لدينا xi غير صحيح، لأننا قمنا بخطأ.
In this case, we're in the second line here.
ونحن في هذه الحالة، على الخط الثاني هنا،
So if it was a good classifier it had the w hat t of 2.3,
حيث إن كان مصنفًا جيدًا، فسيكون به Ŵt يساوي 2.3،
then we're going to multiply the weight by each of the power 2.3,
ومن ثم، فإننا سنقوم بضرب الحجم بكل مرفوع لأس يساوي 2.3.
so this is e to the 2.3, which if you do the math is 9.98, so approximately 10.
ولهذا فإن e مرفوعة لأس 2.3، حيث إن قمت بعملية حسابية تساوي 9.98، فستكون بالتقريب 10.
So it's 10 times bigger.
ولذا، يعد ذلك أكبر بعشر مرات.
And so, what we doing is increasing the importance of this mistake significantly.
ولهذا، ما نقوم به هو زيادة الأهمية لهذا الخطأ بشكل جلي.
So the next classify is going to pay much more attention to this particular data
ولهذا فإن المصنف التالي سيهتم بشكل أكبر بنقاط البيانات المحددة تلك،
point because it was a mistaken one.
حيث إنها كانت خاطئة.
Now finally, just very quickly, what happens if we make a mistake, but
وأخيرًا، وبشكل سريع جدًا، ما الذي يحدث إذا قمنا بخطأ،
we have that random classifier that had weight 0, we didn't care about it.
ولكن يكون لدينا هذا المصنف العشوائي والذي به حجم يساوي 0، والذي لا نآبه له.
So the multiplication here is e0,
ولذا فإن ناتج الضرب هنا يساوي e مرفوعًا ل0.
which is again = 1 which means we keep the importance of this data point the same.
والذي مجددًا يساوي 1، مما يعني أن الأهمية لكلٍ من نقاط البيانات تلك متساوية.
So very good we now seen this cool update from AdaBoost,
ولهذا، فهذا أمر جيد جدًا، حيث نرى الآن هذا التحديث الرائع من AdaBoost،
which makes a ton of sense increase the weights of data points where we made
والذي يسبب زيادة منطقية لأحجام نقاط البيانات،
mistakes and decrease the ones we didn't make mistakes in simulator and
حيث نقوم بالأخطاء ويقلل من تلك التي لا نقوم فيها بأخطاء في المحاكي
we're going to use it in our AdaBoost algorithm.
وسنقوم باستخدامها في خوارزمية AdaBoost الخاصة بنا.
So if we update our algorithm, or
ولذا، إن قمنا بتحديث الخوارزمية الخاصة بنا،
we stacked it with uniform weights, we learned classifier f of t.
أو قمنا بتكديسها من خلال أحجام موحدة، فسنتعلم المصنف f من t.
We updated its, or computed its coefficient, w hat t.
قمنا بتحديثها، أو حساب معاملها Ŵt.
Now we can update the weights of the data points, alpha i.
ويمكننا الآن تحديث الأحجام لنقاط البيانات، ألفا i.
Using the simple formula from the previous slide which increases the weight of
باستخدام الصيغة المبسطة من الشريحة السابقة والتي تزيد من حجم الأخطاء
mistakes, decreases the weights of the correct classifications.
وتقلل الأحجام للتصنيفات الصحيحة.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]